it's crazy that every second you use your smartphone
你使用智能手机的每一秒都很疯狂
there is a chemical reaction
有化学反应
like a baking soda volcano happening inside of it
就像里面发生的小苏打火山
it looks like a solid device without many moving parts
它看起来像一个没有许多活动部件的固体设备
but it's true
但这是真的
inside the battery
电池内部
there is a chemical reaction
有化学反应
that is continuously running
持续运行的
and without it your phone would just be dead
没有它，你的手机就会没电。
which is something we're all familiar with
这是我们都很熟悉的
let's investigate this lithium ion battery
让我们调查一下这个锂离子电池
how does it power your smartphone
它如何为您的智能手机供电？
what happens when you recharge it
充电时会发生什么？
and probably what we're all wondering
也许我们都想知道
why does your battery die
为什么你的电池没电了？
earlier and earlier in the day
一天中越来越早
to answer these questions
来回答这些问题
let's open up this battery and look inside
让我们打开这个电池看看里面
so first how does your battery power your smartphone
那么首先，您的电池如何为智能手机供电？
let's start from what we know
让我们从我们知道的开始
all batteries have a positive terminal
所有电池都有正极端子
and a negative terminal
和一个负终端
and supply power or electricity
并提供电力或电力
to our portable devices
到我们的便携式设备
so electricity is essentially a flow of electrons
所以电本质上是电子的流动
in our smartphone
在我们的智能手机中
electrons which are negatively charged
带负电荷的电子
flow from the negative terminal
从负极流出
and run things like the speakers or the display
并运行扬声器或显示器之类的东西
and then end up in the positive terminal
最后到达正极
so then where does this flow of electrons come from
那么这些电子流是从哪里来的呢？
well this is a lithium ion battery
嗯，这是锂离子电池。
so the electrons come from the element lithium
所以电子来自锂元素
at the negative terminal
在负端
which is technically called the anode
技术上称为阳极
lithium is stored between layers of carbon graphite
锂储存在碳石墨层之间
similar to the graphite in your pencil
类似于你铅笔里的石墨
graphite has a nifty
石墨有一种俏皮
crystal structure of layered planes
层状平面的晶体结构
that allows the lithium
允许锂
to be wedged in between each of the layers
楔入每一层之间
the technical term for this is intercalation
技术术语叫做嵌入
graphite functions as a kind of like
石墨的功能有点像
stable storage space for lithium atoms
锂原子的稳定存储空间
okay moving on
好吧继续
one inherent property of the element lithium
锂元素的一个固有特性
is that it doesn't like its
它不喜欢它的
outermost electron
最外层电子
and it wants to give it up
它想放弃它
when there is an available path
当有可用路径时
from the negative terminal
从负端
to the positive terminal
到正极
this electron separates from the lithium
这个电子与锂原子分离
and starts heading to the other side
并开始前往另一边
at the same time
同时
the lithium leaves the graphite and becomes positively
锂离开石墨变成正极
or 1 charged and is now called a lithium ion
或1充电，现在称为锂离子
FYI an ion is just a fancy word for an atom
仅供参考离子只是原子的花哨说法
who has lost or gained an electron
谁失去或获得了一个电子
and thus is charged
因此被收费
when a lot of lithium atoms leave the graphite
当大量锂原子离开石墨
at the same time
同时
a flow of electrons is built up
形成了一股电子流
so let's now jump to the positive terminal
现在让我们跳到正极
which is technically called the cathode
技术上称为阴极
here we have cobalt
这里有钴
which has lost some electrons to oxygen
因为氧气而失去了一些电子
thus making the cobalt positive or
从而使钴呈阳性或
4 charged as a result it wants to gain back an electron
4带电，结果它想重获一个电子
so when we connect the negative and positive terminals
所以当我们连接负极和正极端子时
to our smartphone
到我们的智能手机
the electrons flow from the lithium
电子从锂中流出
which wants to give up an electron
它想放弃一个电子
through the circuits and components in the smartphone
通过智能手机中的电路和组件
and to the cobalt which wants to gain an electron
对于想要获得电子的钴
now here we run into a small issue
现在我们遇到了一个小问题
with the flow of electrons
随着电子的流动
from the negative to the positive terminal
从负极到正极
the cobalt side
钴的一面
grows more and more negatively charged
越来越带负电荷
and the other side positively charged
另一边带正电
yes the electrons do want to flow in this direction
是的，电子确实想朝这个方向流动
but at the same time
但同时
electrons don't like to flow to an area
电子不喜欢流向一个区域
that is growing more and more negatively charged
这是越来越多的负电荷
this is because opposite charges attract
这是因为相反的电荷吸引
and similar charges repel
和类似的指控相斥
so to fix this
所以为了解决这个问题
we give the now positively charged lithium ions
我们给现在带正电荷的锂离子
that recently left the graphite
最近离开石墨的
a path to move to the other side
一条通往另一边的道路
this path is called an electrolyte
这条路称为电解质
and its function
及其功能
allows for the lithium ions to migrate
允许锂离子迁移
over from one side
从一边过来
to the other
到另一个
while not allowing the electrons to move through it
同时不允许电子穿过它
when lithium gets to the cobalt side
当锂元素到达钴元素一侧时
it again wedges itself or intercalates
它再次楔入或插入
with the cobalt and oxygen to become lithium cobalt
用钴和氧变成锂钴
oxide the lithium isn't regaining its electron
氧化锂无法重新获得电子
that electron went to the cobalt
那个电子去了钴
it's just balancing out the charge buildup
它只是平衡电荷堆积
let's quickly recap
让我们快速总结一下
here is a full battery
这是一个完整的电池
throughout the day
全天
lithium atoms leave the graphite layers
锂原子离开石墨层
and separate from their electrons
并与它们的电子分离
to become lithium ions
变成锂离子
the electrons flow from the negative terminal
电子从负极流出
through the circuits and components in the smartphone
通过智能手机中的电路和组件
and into the positive terminal
并进入正终端
to join the cobalt atoms
加入钴原子
at the same time
同时
the lithium ions travel through the electrolyte
锂离子穿过电解质
in order to neutralize the charge buildup
为了中和电荷堆积
and keep the reaction going
并保持反应
here's the chemical formula for the reaction
这是反应的化学式
thus at the end of the day
因此在一天结束时
almost all of the lithium has left the graphite layers
几乎所有的锂都离开了石墨层
and joined the cobalt to become lithium cobalt oxide
并加入钴成为锂钴氧化物
and your battery is now running on empty
你的电池现在空了。
now that the battery is empty let's recharge it
现在电池没电了，让我们给它充电。
we plug in our smartphone and when we do this
我们插入智能手机，当我们这样做时
the USB charger applies a higher force
USB充电器施加更大的力
on a flow of electrons
在电子流上
in the opposite direction
在相反的方向
electrons are pulled out of the cobalt
电子从钴中被拉出
thus returning cobalt to its
从而将钴返回其
4 state and kicking out the lithium ions
4种状态并踢出锂离子
on the other side
在另一边
electrons are forced onto the graphite
电子被压在石墨上
which pulls the lithium through the electrolyte
它将锂拉过电解质
and back into the layers of graphite
回到石墨层
as you see
如你所见
it's the exact opposite of the earlier reaction
这和之前的反应完全相反
which is why this battery is rechargeable
这就是为什么这个电池是可充电的
the lithium and its electrons move in one direction
锂和它的电子向一个方向移动
when you use the phone
当你使用电话时
and the opposite when you charge it back up
当你重新充电时，情况正好相反
okay
好吧
so now let's rewind and add a few more details of note
所以现在让我们倒带并添加更多的注意细节
first these two sides can't touch
首先这两面不能碰
if the anode and cathode were to touch
如果阳极和阴极接触
and if there were any lithium left in the graphite
如果石墨里还有锂
the chemical reaction would accelerate uncontrollably
化学反应会不受控制地加速
and cause a fire or often a small explosion
并引起火灾或通常是小爆炸
thus a non conductive semi permeable separator
因此是一种不导电的半渗透隔板
that allows the lithium ions to pass through
允许锂离子通过
is placed in the middle
被放在中间
and this electrolyte
这种电解质
isn't an effective barrier because it's a liquid
不是有效的屏障因为它是液体
the second thing to note is that the graphite
第二件要注意的是石墨
and cobalt peroxide
和过氧化钴
aren't good at collecting
不擅长收集
or distributing the electrons
或者分配电子
thus a conductive copper layer is added next to the
因此，导电铜层被添加到旁边
graphite and a conductive aluminum layer
石墨和导电铝层
next to the cobalt peroxide
在过氧化钴旁边
these two layers or sheets are called collectors
这两层或片材称为收集器
okay on to third
好的到第三个
these animations are showing
这些动画正在展示
100 percent of the lithium moving from the anode
100%的锂从阳极移动
to the cathode and back
到阴极再回来
but in reality
但实际上
there will always be some percentage of lithium
总会有一定比例的锂
that remains in the anode
仍然在阳极中
cathode and electrolyte
阴极和电解质
despite the battery being fully charged or discharged
尽管电池充满电或放电
respectively
分别
continuing to fourth
继续到第四
in order to maximize the capacity of the battery
为了最大限度地提高电池的容量
and allow the battery to fit in your smartphone
并让电池适合您的智能手机
all these layers are folded
所有这些层都折叠了
and wrapped into a rectangular prism package
并包裹成长方形棱镜包装
ugh
唉
I know this is a lot but 5th and final
我知道这是很多，但第五名也是最后一名。
in order to regulate the flow of electricity
为了调节电流
additional circuitry is added
添加了额外的电路
to the top of the battery
到电池顶部
this circuitry prevents overcharging
该电路可防止过度充电
and damage to the battery
和电池损坏
so then the final
那么决赛
why does your battery's max capacity reduce over time
为什么电池的最大容量会随着时间的推移而减少？
there are several reasons
有几个原因
one of which is that sometimes
其中之一就是有时候
lithium and the incoming electron
锂和入射电子
react with the electrolyte and organic solvent to form
与电解质和有机溶剂反应形成
compounds
化合物
that are called solid electrolyte interface or Sei
被称为固体电解质界面或Sei
SEIS irreversibly consume lithium and the electrolyte
SEIS不可逆地消耗锂和电解质
thus reducing the overall quantity of lithium
从而减少锂的总量
and thereby reducing the max capacity of your battery
从而降低电池的最大容量
another reason is that
另一个原因是
when you fully discharge your battery
当您将电池完全放电时
until it's dead
直到它死了
it can result in too much lithium on the cobalt side
它会导致钴侧有太多的锂
which causes the irreversible generation of lithium
导致锂的不可逆生成
oxide and cobalt
氧化物和钴
2 oxide these compounds are stuck in that state
2氧化物这些化合物停留在那个状态
which thereby
从而
reduces the amount of lithium and cobalt
减少锂和钴的量
for future use
供将来使用
so one tip is to not let your battery run
所以一个提示是不要让你的电池运行
until it's empty
直到它空了
it's better to recharge your battery at
最好给电池充电
30 or 40 percent than to let it run until it's dead
30%或40%比让它一直运行到死
that about wraps it up
那就差不多结束了
when it comes to batteries
说到电池
there are hundreds of different chemistry
有数百种不同的化学物质
and compounds that allow them to work
以及让它们发挥作用的化合物
but they all work on similar principles
但它们都遵循相似的原理
you just need three materials
你只需要三种材料
one that wants electrons
想要电子的人
one that wants to give up electrons
一个想放弃电子的人
and then a path for the buildup of charge
然后是电荷积累的路径
to neutralize
中和
thanks for watching
感谢收看
here are 3 questions I'm going to leave you with
这里有三个问题我将留给你们
discuss them in the comments
在评论中讨论它们
also ask questions in the comments
也在评论中提问
if you do it
如果你做了
I will pin the top questions for further discussion
我将确定首要问题以供进一步讨论
don't forget to subscribe
别忘了订阅
and tell your friends and family about something
告诉你的朋友和家人一些事情
you Learned today
你今天学到了
this episode is about lithium ion smartphone batteries
这一集是关于锂离子智能手机电池的
and it branches
它的分支
to electric vehicle batteries
到电动汽车电池
discussed by Learn Engineering
学习工程讨论
we recommend you take a look
我们建议您看看
it also connects to galvanic and voltaic cells
它还连接到原电池和伏打电池
chemical bonds and electro negativity
化学键和电负性
and lemon batteries
和柠檬电池
post your comments with further questions
发表您的评论并提出进一步的问题
answers and thoughts
答案和想法
and remember
并记住
conceptual simplicity and structural complexity
概念简单性和结构复杂性